[Music]
foreign
the options for foraging this time of
year are quite limited of course but I
am out and about trying to find some
nice pieces of bark and some little you
know pieces of moss and other bits of
nature for a project I have in mind so
that is what I'm up to this morning and
it is freezing cold and there's hor
Frost over everything and I don't know
how much longer I'm going to be able to
stand being outdoors so we're gonna get
to it and then go home and work on a
little project
hi there come on
I don't travel far from my valley in
general and certainly not in Winter as
mountain roads are often closed making
it difficult to leave this year I found
myself caught up in routine splitting my
time between work and family and repeat
it's habitual predictable steady
over time I've grown to Value this
feeling knowing that there are so many
different ways I could live and yet this
one works the best for me routine helps
me feel calm and living without constant
change is a contrast to a childhood of
moving often
in many ways my days are quite mundane
perhaps a bit boring in the way that
they don't seem exciting from the
outside
we follow the rhythms of Dawn and dusk
in the seasons in the winter I am
indoors in the summer I feel as if I
live among the flowers in the forest
I thought I would share some ways that I
make life interesting particularly when
I've been stuck in routine
the first is inspired by a guided
Journal I've been working through that
encourages everyone to find a safe place
Outdoors to stargaze or if stars are not
visible where you live to visit a
planetarium or watch night sky and space
documentaries to add their awareness in
all of the world beyond the clouds
[Music]
foreign
Luke and his father make a lot of things
out of wood they're Woodworkers and they
used to work in construction and so they
have a lot of leftover tools and
supplies and Luke gave me some of this
lovely natural wood stain that I am able
to use in order to stain some of these
decorative pieces that I would like to
experiment with putting them up around
the house and seeing how they look I
have a feeling they will look quite
lovely however I just had to take a
moment and pause and tell you that
something about dipping the paintbrush
in this oil
and
seeing the colors transform as I paint
this piece of wood with the stain and
just seeing how rich the golden wood
color is during this project reminded me
of when I started working at a preschool
and one of the first projects I made for
the children there was that I went and I
collected a lot of little stones and
Pebbles from the river and I let them
dry and then I put them on a little tray
with a cup and some water and a
paintbrush to let them paint the stones
with water and see how the colors change
as it comes in contact with the
paintbrush and the children just love
that activity it was so calming and
enjoyable and I was thinking about that
and just having a wonderful time doing
this so next time you see yourself near
a body of water do consider taking a
pebble and putting it under water and
enjoying how the colors change
you might find it to be quite calming
and enjoyable or extremely childish I
don't know I guess it depends on who you
are but I've been embracing rather
childish activities lately and um I've
been enjoying it thoroughly
so once this dries I'm gonna take it
downstairs and experiment with it a
little bit and see where it would look
most lovely
[Music]
good boy
so this is my idea I think that since it
has the same stain as the wood it Blends
in quite well and I have these round
ones as well that I thought could just
make lovely little wall decorations so
I'm experimenting so here is a home
craft idea that's very simple if you
want to try it to make your home look
extra Whimsical or strange however you
interpret it
oh
foreign
I like to do to add a bit of magic to my
day is to read stories about my
ancestors I'm yet to come across a myth
or legend that isn't fascinating
at the end of this video I will tell a
story of my people I think it is so
important to keep these stories alive
and to remind us that we're connected to
something ancient as well as something
modern it makes me aware that my life is
part of a greater story despite things
seeming quite uninspiring sometimes when
I get caught up in present concerns
foreign
I also encourage you to create in some
shape or form or even just a little now
and then even if you're not usually
creative the famous Victorian William
Morris was known to say that handmade
items arts and crafts hold the essence
of the artist and a little piece of a
soul that is lacking in the factory made
equivalents
I like to interpret this idea as when
something has a story an individual
effort put behind it it becomes more
special
I think this extends to poetry and
writing as well it doesn't need to turn
out perfectly for it to have a little
sacred Essence in it having been created
with gentle thoughts and patient hands
lastly the simplest way I keep life
interesting and my spirit happy is to
allow myself to grow and evolve and to
learn something new
I think that it is easy to often stay
where we're comfortable and not question
ourselves our relationships what is
nurturing us and what is not I find
reading books on various subjects on
mindfulness and even some on a variety
of different belief systems challenges
and AIDS me and being more understanding
and open
I hope you never forget that you are
wondrous as we enter a new and sometimes
daunting year we know that despite
challenges we can make it into something
imperfectly beautiful and the ordinary
aspects of Our Lives if lived with love
and enthusiasm is what makes us
extraordinary at the end of the day
[Music]
foreign
I apologize if there's a little bit of
noise in the background today there's a
lot going on in the house
I have been working on videos at a much
slower Pace than usual this month I have
been trying to really listen to myself
and not overdo things as I usually like
to do so I will let you know in advance
you know that my videos may not come
quite on the same schedule as they used
to but I'm doing my best and in the
meantime I hope to just really be able
to put extra time and effort into the
videos I create this week again was
quite tricky as I got a bit of a cold at
the beginning of the week and it threw
things off but I'm feeling much better
and just getting back into the rhythm of
things as I said earlier I did want to
share one of the legends that I was once
told and you might enjoy it as well and
I encourage you to look into the Legends
and myths of your own ancestry because I
think that no matter where you come from
there's always so many interesting Rich
details to learn about that really add
to your awareness of yourself and where
you come from there are quite a few
Legends and myths I could share from my
father's side of the family
that are more Celtic in origin but I
think that a lot of those are more well
known I thought I would share one
instead of my mother's side of the
family from Puerto Rico and this one is
a specific version of this story I'm
sure the version is drastically
different depending on what store you
look at or who you talk to so this is
just my version this Story begins with a
young woman who is atainino who are
indigenous de Puerto Rico and her father
is a great and powerful kasike which is
a chief this young girl loves to spend
time out in nature and she absolutely
loves the flowers and the birds and
spends a lot of I'm daydreaming one day
she meets a boy who is a carob who is
from a different group of people and she
falls in love and The Sun Shines down on
them and is so happy to see their
youthful and innocent love that they
share together however her father the
kasike is not happy about their Union so
her father says that she has no other
options but to marry someone in her
tribe and forget about that boy she had
fallen in love with that young woman
went out in nature again and asked the
gods to be able to do something so that
she would not have to marry this man she
did not love and she could be with this
boy and so her prayers in a way were
answered because she was turned into a
flower and the boy was turned into a
hummingbird and whenever you see a
hummingbird going from flower to flower
to flower looking for nectar the
hummingbird is actually looking for
their lost love and so the hummingbird
will continue looking for nectar at each
flower until they eventually get
reunited with the woman they loved I
think that is such a sweet story and
varying tradition with a lot of the
myths and legends you may already know
when I think about it I actually think
of Romeo and Juliet as it's kind of a
quite similar storyline I could tell you
countless stories but I will end it
there but that is one of my favorites
on another note I wanted to say a big
thank you to everyone who has taken the
time to review my book either on Amazon
or any other platform it means so much
to be able to get feedback and to
hopefully be able to improve my writing
in the future it was such a big
undertaking and getting some feedback
has just been really special on another
note this is not sponsored but I
recently received these perfume oils as
a gift and I thought I would just
mention them just because I love them
and I've been using them especially when
I've been getting over my cold something
about Cozy smells really helps me feel a
little bit better one is called Elven
Courtyard and the other is tree nymph
Palace and they are obviously inspired
by fairies and folklore which is exactly
you know everything that I love
so I'll leave the information Down Below
in case you're interested I I just
wanted to mention it just because I've
really really been enjoying them lately
now that you watched me cover a lot of
random topics if you are still here
thank you my head is still in a bit of a
fog since getting over my cold so I
appreciate your patience and I will see
you very soon I hope you have a
wonderful week take care goodbye
[Music]
thank you
foreign